-你开车  我骑车  -好的
- You drive, I'll ride. - All right.
-单腿跪地  -对  她是个好女孩
- On one knee? - Yes, that's a good girl.
怎么了  卡塞尔  你在求婚吗
What's up, Castle, you proposing?
不  在等你来呢
Oh, no. Just waiting for you.
那真糟糕  你们两个挺般配的
That's too bad.  You two make a cute couple.
没错  你看我养条狗怎么样
Yeah. Hey, you think I should get a dog?
你当我是谁  你妻子吗
What am I, your wife?
你是我工作上的伴侣
Yeah, you're my work-wife.
我才不是你工作伴侣呢
No, I'm not your workwife.
我可以养条猎犬  名字就叫夏洛克[福尔摩斯]
I could get a bloodhound. I could name him Sherlock,
然后还可以它带到犯罪现场
And then I could--  I could bring him to crime scenes.
不可以
No, you couldn't.
怎么了  狗狗很可爱
Oh, what? It'd be adorable.
再给它带一顶小号侦探帽
I could get him to wear a little Sherlock hat,
训练它叼着放大镜
Train him how to carry a little magnifying glass.
发现没  你刚才说的
Oh, see? Right there.
反对我  说我错  分明就是我的工作伴侣
Disapproving, judgmental-- you're totally my work-wife.
这血迹也太明显了  但会是个好线索
Oh, the blood's bold, but it works.
不知他是否同意
Not sure he'd agree.
很明显  他  醉心艺术
Well, obviously, he was-- into art.
受害者芬克  43岁  画廊主人
Victor Fink, 43, gallery owner.
没有强行进入的痕迹
There's no sign of forced entry.
楼上的房客晚上10点14分听到枪声报警
Tenant upstairs call in gunshots to 9-1-1 at 10:14 p.m.
知道他为何这么晚在这吗
Any idea what he was  doing here so late?
不清楚  但据他助手达里斯·兰利交代
No, but according to his assistant, Darius Langley,
-他们8点就关门了  -据他所言
- They close at 8:00. - Far as he can tell,
墙上和仓库中的画没有丢失
There's nothing missing off the walls or from the back.
监控录像能看出什么吗
Anything off those security cameras?
-假的  没有接线  -凶手够幸运的
- Fake. Not even hooked up. - Lucky break for the guy.
除非他早知道这点  而且知道芬克会加班
Unless he knew, just like he knew Fink was working late.
或是计划好约他到这里  再问问助手
Or made plans to meet him here. Check with the assistant.
死者与凶手搏斗过
He had some fight in him.
前臂和手部有擦伤
Abrasions on the forearms, on the hands.
然后他从楼梯逃跑
And then he made a run for the stairs.
背后中枪
Only to be shot in the back.
两枪  9毫米口径
Twice, 9 millimeter.
凶手是在那里开枪
Shooter fired from over here.
有没有可能是他约了人
Is it possible he might have been meeting somebody?
就算他在见人  也没告诉我
If he was meeting someone, he didn't tell me.
打扰一分钟
Excuse me for a minute.
我八点锁门  他就已经离开了
He'd already left by the time I locked up at 8:00.
兰利先生  我是凯特·贝克特探长
Mr. Langley, I'm detective Kate Beckett.
-你给芬克先生做助手多久了  -两个月
- How long have you been Mr. Fink's assistant? - Two months.
我是艺术系学生  在蒂彻艺术学院上夜校
I'm an art student. I take night classes at Tisch.
所以你昨晚在学校吗
Is that where you were tonight?
是的  芬克先生很支持我上学
Yeah, Mr. Fink totally supported me being in school.
他让我提前离开去上课
He'd let me leave early to make classes.
你们打给我的时候  我也在学校
That's where I was when you guys called.
芬克先生有没有什么仇人
Do you know if Mr. Fink had any enemies,
相处不愉快的客户或画家
Any unhappy clients or artists?
没什么不寻常的
Nothing out of the ordinary.
如果有需要  我可以给你份通讯录
I can get you a contact list if you like.
好的  麻烦了
Yes, please.
现在有个小问题
Hey, we got a little problem.
我们从墙上取出两颗弹头
We dug these two slugs out of the wall.
还算完整  看看弹道测试
They're not very fragmented. See if ballistics
是否与其他枪击案相同
Can run a match on any of the other shooting the city.
当然  但这不是问题所在
Sure, but that's not the problem.
我们从墙上取出这两颗弹头
We dug these two out of the wall,
而帕里什医生从死者身上取出另外两颗
And Dr. Parish has another two in our vic here.
所以凶手并非神枪手
So our perp's not a sharpshooter.
但我们只发现四颗子弹
But we've only found four bullets,
而地上有1  2  3  4  5块弹壳
And there are 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 shell casings on the ground.
外面也没有血迹
There's no blood trail leading out of here.
正是  而且死者的血
Exactly, and not a drop of blood
一滴也没有溅到外面
Outside of the spatter from our vic here.
那么说没有第二个死者了
So there's no second victim?
那么  第五颗子弹在哪里
So where's the fifth bullet?
那子弹是冰块做的
The bullet was made of ice.
好的  对  带她过来
Okay, great. Yeah, send her up.
芬克的妻子来了
Fink's wife is on her way up.
开枪后  子弹就融化了
Fires the bullet. It melts before we can find it.
一颗冰弹
An ice bullet.
喂  冰弹  你没在听吗
Hello. An ice bullet, are you even paying attention to me?
没有  你说的没一句值得听的
No. You aren't saying anything worth paying attention to.
伙计们还在排查
Yo. Uniforms are still canvassing,
目前  他们没在画廊外发现任何血迹
But so far, they still haven't found any blood trails outside the gallery.
而且鉴证小组两次重新勘察现场
And C.S.U.'s reswept the scene twice.
还是找不到第五颗子弹
No sigh of our fifth bullet.
-我说过了  冰弹  -不  老兄
- I'm telling you, ice bullet. - Nah, bro.
冰弹也会留下弹孔
An ice bullet would still make a bullet hole.
-冰弹孔  -你刚才叫我什么
- You mean ice hole. - What'd you just call me?
伙计们  还有什么消息
Guys, what else?
我们查了芬克的手机记录
We checked Fink's cell phone record.
晚上9点19分  他接了个电话
He got a call at 9:19 p.m.,
即遇害前一小时接到未知来电
An hour before he was killed, from a blocked cell phone number.
通话记录表明那个电话来自纽约
Phone records indicate that the call originated here in New York,
但那是个国际号码  卫星电话
But it was an international cell--satellite phone--
在巴林岛[国家名]手机公司注册
Registered to Bahrain cellular.
那祝你们能得到巴林岛的搜查令
Well, good luck getting a warrant from the government of Bahrain.
查一下芬克的客户和画家通讯录
Run down Fink's client and artist list,
看看有没有国际号码
See if any of them had international numbers,
还有别多嘴
And watch your mouth.
我要去10-1区
I'm gonna go 10-1.
莱恩  有空吗
Hey, Ryan. Got a sec?
目击者吗
Witness?
不算是  在这等会  好吗
Not exactly. Hang here, buddy, okay?
没问题
Of course.
在画廊周围排查时  发现此人
I found him on the canvass by the art gallery.
身上没有钱包  身份证
I mean, the guy's got no wallet, no I.D.
好  那你问过他的姓名了吗
Okay, did you ask him his name?
对  我问了他姓名  住址
Yeah, I asked him his name. I asked him where he lived.
但  有趣的是
You know, but--but here's the funny part--
他说不记得了
Guy says he don't remember.
我丈夫有没有仇人  是  他有
Did my husband have enemies? Yeah, he had enemies.
作品未被收录的画家
Every artist who couldn't  get in his gallery
以及作品被收录的画家都是
And every artist who was in his gallery.
他卖出  比如五幅画
He'd sell, like, five pieces,
他们会想知道为什么没卖六幅
And they'd want to know why he didn't sell six.
芬克太太  我知道你心烦意乱
Mrs. Fink, I know you're upset--
不  你说我该怎么面对这些
No, what am I supposed to do with these, huh?
我才不想变成这样
I didn't want 'em.
为了他我才去做的  现在他死了
I did it for him, and now he's dead.
芬克太太  有没有谁
Mrs. Fink, can you think of anyone
对你丈夫愤恨至极
Who would hate your husband enough
-残忍地在他背后开枪  -罗柯
- To shoot him in cold blood in the back? - Rocco.
-罗柯  画家之一吗  -他的助手
- Rocco? Was that one of the artists? - His assistant.
我记得达里斯是他的助手
I thought Darius was his assistant.
罗柯是前任  维克多几个月前炒了他
His old assistant. Victor fired Rocco a few months back.
-为什么  -因为钱  炒了那小子
- Why? - He fired that little insect over money.
罗柯简直疯了  以各种方式威胁于他
Boy, did Rocco go crazy, making all kinds of threats.
"你会找你报仇的  芬克"  但知道吗
"I'm gonna get you, Fink."  But you know what?
就凭罗柯  他根本算不上个男人
No. Rocco? He wasn't even a man.
他就像是个小跳蚤
He was more like a flea.
维克多根本没放在心上
Victor didn't even think twice about it.
假设小跳蚤有把枪
You suppose the Flea had a gun,
一把小枪和会消失的子弹
A tiny gun with vanishing bullets?
冰弹和带枪的跳蚤
Ice bullets and Fleas with guns--
作家的大脑又没法思考了
Do you have writer's block again?
史蒂芬·金写的那本
Stephen King wrote stories
《嗜血魔车》系列卖了上千万册
Of Bloodthirsty Cars and sold millions of copies.
我觉得  不必被逻辑所局限
I figure, why be limited by logic?
罗柯·琼斯  芬克以前的助手
Rocco Jones, Fink's old assistant.
他妻子说
The wife said that
罗柯给芬克打过恐吓电话
Rocco called and left threatening messages for Fink.
-看看有什么发现  -这就去
- See what you can find. - I'm on it.
莱恩在干什么
Hey, what's up with Ryan?
抢劫案
Mugging case.
那家伙头部受创  记不得自己是谁
The guy got hit in the head and can't remember who he is.
子弹消失的情节很酷  但失忆症更酷
Oh, missing bullets are cool. Amnesia is even cooler.
我想你肯定还有更重要的事要做
I'm sure you have better things to do.
我肯定也有
I'm sure I do, too.
气雾剂  你有哮喘
An inhaler. You're asthmatic.
棒极了
Awesome.
你还是留着这个吧
Y-you should probably hang on to that.
气雾剂  食品袋  钥匙
Inhaler, grocery bag, keys--
你是说你对这些东西
Are you telling me you don't remember at all
完全没印象
What any of that is for?
对  真是可笑啊
Yeah. How ridiculous is that?
那么说  他失忆了吗
So has he, uh, really got amnesia?
是的  但很明显  我的听力没问题
Yeah, but apparently, my hearing's fine.
那很好  我是理查德·卡塞尔
Well, that's good.  Richard Castle.
我也想来个自我介绍
I'd introduce myself, too--
我们在看他兜里
Yeah, we're just going through his pockets,
有没有能表明他身份的东西
Trying to find something that could tell us who he is.
很明显  我还在看书
Oh, and apparently I've been reading as well.
《罪与罚》  陀思妥也夫斯基  经典之作
Ah, "Crime and Punishment," Dostoyevsky. Classic.
-很有品味  -卡塞尔
- You have excellent taste. - Castle.
9毫米口径
9 millimeter.
我想我们找到第五颗子弹了
I think we just found our fifth bullet.
《灵书妙探》
第二季  第十一集
如果我们养条狗
You know what? If we got a dog,
我可以给它买个挂包
I could buy him little saddlebags,
它就能给你把书带到学校
And then he could carry your books to school,
你就不必担心脊椎侧弯了
And you wouldn't have to worry about getting scoliosis.
概念上说  我和你一样喜欢狗
Conceptually, I'd like a dog as much as you would.
但在现实中
In reality,
我不认为吃完饭不收盘子的家伙
I'm not seeing the guy whose dishes never make it to the sink
能在哈德森公园弯腰铲狗屎
Bending over to scoop poop in Hudson park.
我打赌我能训练它去厕所便便
I bet I could train him to use a toilet.
奶奶  我以为你在房间睡觉
Gram. I thought you were sleeping in.
刚才在睡  不过没在我房间
I was, just not in my room.
知道吗  我们交流的有点多
You know what? We all share way too much.
抱歉  宝贝
Oh, I'm sorry, kiddo.
但我的快乐无法抑制
But my happiness cannot be contained.
我去上学了  很高兴你约会愉快
I'm going to school. Yes. I'm glad you had a nice date.
三  四  五
...Three and four and five.
从你糟糕的仪表推测
I am assuming from this walk of shame...
你和你的高中情人查特
That you and your high school sweetheart Chet
愉快地畅谈了一晚
Had a lovely night all night talking.
-在其他事情之间  -已经有几周了
- Among other things. - It's a been a few weeks.
我要不要请他坐下  问问他的意思呢
Do I need to sit him down and ask him his intentions?
我玩得很高兴  不必担心他的意思
I am having way too much fun to worry about his intentions.
我们享用了美好的烛光晚餐
Okay, took me for lovely candlelight dinner...
马车经过中心公园
Horse and carriage ride through central park,
我们坐在一块巨石上看日出
Where we watched the sunrise over the same boulder
当年我们就在那里彼此献出初吻
Where we shared our first kiss.
等等  你们在那里过的夜
Wait. That's still his make-out spot?
妈妈  这样很危险
Mother, that's a red flag.
宝贝  你说什么也破坏不了我的兴致
Honey, nothing you could say can spoil this for me.
我很久没有这种感觉了  自从...
I haven't felt this way since...
记不得自从什么时候了
I can't remember when.
失忆症啊  现在流行
Ah, amnesia. It's going around.
说到这个  我要出门了
Speaking of which, I'm off.
我想要告诉你不用等我了
I'd tell you not to wait up,
可是显然  没这个必要了
But clearly, there would be no point.
系统没有记录他的指纹
His fingerprints aren't in the system,
失踪人口里也没有什么发现
And we don't have any hits on missing persons.
真是疯狂  我们找到了案子的目击者
This is crazy. We actually find a witness to our murder,
但我们不知道他是谁
We don't know who he is,
他也记不得看到过什么
And he doesn't remember what he saw.
罗柯那边的进展怎么样了
Where are we on Rocco?
芬克的前任助手吗
Fink's old assistant?
正在带他过来
Uniforms are bringing him in now.
弹道测试证实这颗子弹
Ballistics confirms the bullet
和其他子弹来自同一把枪
Come from the same gun as the others.
不管画廊发生了什么  他都在现场
Whatever happened in the gallery, he was there.
不仅如此  凶手还想灭口
Not only was he there, but someone tried to kill him as well.
-很幸运他带着书  -读的还是俄国文学
- Good thing he reads. - Good thing he reads Russian literature.
如果他迷尼古拉斯·斯帕克斯  就死定了
If the guy was a Nicolas Sparks' fan, he'd be dead.
让鉴证小组检查外套上
Have C.S.U. check the coat
残留的火药  血迹和纤维
For gunpowder residue, blood, fibers.
或许能说明当晚的情况
Maybe it can tell us what happened that night.
查查芬克的画家和客户的身份证照片
And check photo I.D.s on Fink's artists and clients.
你认为凶手是其中之一
You think he might be on of 'em?
女人总是抱着幻想的
A girl can dream.
我给你拿了咖啡
I brought you coffee.
谢谢  卡塞尔
Thank you, Castle.
我们的记忆分为三种类型
We all have three different types of memory.
一般的知识  比如语言和事实
General knowledge, like language and facts,
这叫作语义记忆
Is called semantic memory.
在这部分  你完全没有问题
Yours doesn't seem to be affected.
还有程序记忆
Then there's procedural memory,
也叫肌肉记忆
Also often called muscle memory.
其中包括
That includes any actions or skills
你不断重复的行为和技巧
That you've repeated over and over
逐渐形成了神经通路
And formed neural pathways for,
比如骑自行车  这点你也没问题
Like riding a bike. Now I know it is intact.
因为你可以行走自如
Because you've been walking around.
所以问题是什么  医生
So what's the problem, doc?
问题在于情节性记忆
The problem is in episodic memory.
你所经历过的事
That's any experience you've ever had--
对话  看过的电影
Conversations, movies you've seen,
认识的人  甚至你自己的名字
The people in your life, even your own name.
就好像  如果我是一名赌徒
So, like, if I were a betting man,
但却不记得自己是赌徒
Which I have no idea if I am,
我能赌记忆可以恢复吗
Would I put my money on my memory coming back?
还是不可以
Or not?
很难讲
There's no way to tell.
也许可以恢复全部记忆
You might eventually get it all back
也许不能  或是恢复一部分
Or none of it or anything in between.
能知道其中的原因吗
Do we know why this would've happened?
他后脑受到撞击
He's got a bump on the back of his head.
头部的撞击通常伴随心理创伤
It's usually a blow to the head coupled with psychological trauma
导致失忆
Which leads to amnesia.
创伤
Trauma?
你确实中了枪  是这意思吗
You did get shot. Could that be it?
如果他相信他命不久矣  就会这样
If he believed he was going to die, then sure.
如果我们带他回到犯罪现场
If we took him back to the scene of the crime,
可以刺激他的记忆吗
Could that jog his memory?
有可能  但是失忆症很棘手
Possibly. But amnesia's a tricky condition.
我要带他回圣文森特
I'd like to take him back to St. Vincent's,
做一些测试和扫描  安全起见
Run some tests and scans, just to be safe.
当然  我先问一些问题
Of course. I'll need to ask a few questions first.
先生
Mister...
抱歉  我不知道怎么称呼你
I'm sorry. I don't even know what to call you.
我也不知道我的名字
I don't know what to call me either.
-你说他的程序性记忆还在  -没错
- You said his procedural memory is intact.   - Yes.
-我可以  -当然
- May I?  - Sure.
签在下面
Just sign at the bottom.
真奇怪  怎么回事
That's freaky. How'd I-- how'd I do that?
-看起来像真的签名  -可能是
- That looks like a real signature. - Well, it probably is.
人们多次重复签名
You've signed your name so many times
已经形成了神经通路  程序性记忆
You've formed neural pathways, procedural memory.
他不记得自己的名字  但却记得签名
So he can't remember his name, but he can sign it?
-神秘的大脑  -字迹很模糊
- Mysteries of the brain.  - It's illegible.
也许你是一名医生
Maybe you're a doctor.
第一个字好像是杰
This first initial looks like a "j."
-有印象吗  -不
- Does that ring a bell?  - No. Unh-unh.
也许我们暂时叫你杰
Maybe we should just call you Jay.
杰  总比没有强
Jay. That's as good as anything, I guess.
你认识这人吗
Do you recognize this man?
不  我应该认识吗
No. Should I?
他叫维克多·芬克
His name is Victor Fink.
你中枪的画廊就是他的
He owned the art gallery where you were shot.
他当时也在那里吗
He was there with me?
他被枪杀了
He was shot and killed.
天啊
God.
这个呢  罗柯·琼斯
What about this man? Rocco Jones.
他曾是画廊的工作人员
He is the worker in gallery
各位  我很没用
Guys, I feel so useless.
我真的  真的很抱歉
Look, I'm really... I'm really sorry.
我认不出他
I-I just don't know him.
我为你做了这么多  芬克
After all I did for you, Fink?
我不只是你的助理
I wasn't just your assistant, man.
我为你犯法
I broke the law for you.
你以为能就这样炒了我吗
And you think you can just fire me?
我就应该杀了你  从背后崩了你
I should kill you, man. Just pop you right in the back.
砰  你就是死人一个
Bang! And you're dead.
你最终还是鼓起勇气杀了他  罗柯
So you finally get the courage to do it, there, Rocco?
老兄  我昏了头  发发脾气而已
Dude, come on. I was mad. I was just blowing off steam.
你说你为他做犯法的事
You said you broke the law for him.
怎么回事
How?
算了  伙计
Fine by me, pal.
等着上法庭吧
You have a nice trial.
得了  你在说什么鬼话
Come on. What the hell are you talking about?
你恐吓某人  然后他死了
You threatened a guy, then he turns up dead.
好好算算
Do the math.
造假
Forgeries.
芬克雇我帮他做高级画作的赝品
Fink paid me to paint forgeries of high-end paintings.
我挣扎过  但我需要钱
Look, I was struggling, man. I needed the dough.
他怎么处理赝品
What'd he do with the copies?
卖了
Sold them.
当成真品卖给买家
Passed them along to the buyer like they were the real thing.
卖给谁
Who did he sell to?
巴希尔·哈伦
Bahir Harun.
他是巴林领事馆的外交人员
He's an attacher at the Bahrain consulate.
巴林人  芬克在遇害一小时前
Bahrain? So he's the one who talked to Fink
通话的那个人
An hour before he was murdered.
也许他知道了芬克卖的是赝品
Maybe he figured out Fink was selling fakes
决定要报复
And decided to get even.
这都不要紧
Doesn't matter.
这家伙有完全外交豁免权
The guy has full diplomatic immunity.
很好
Great.
我检查了芬克所有的顾客和画家的
So I checked all the photo I.D.s
身份证照片
Of all of Fink's clients and artists.
我们的朋友杰不在其中
Our friend Jay isn't one of them.
那他当时在画廊里干什么
Then what was he doing at the gallery?
霍洛威医生从医院来电
Holloway called from the hospital.
杰除了头部的小撞击  身体无恙
Aside from a minor head bump, Jay's got a clean bill of health.
当然  除了失忆
Well, other than the memory loss.
你们带杰回到罪案现场
You know what? Why don't you guys grab jay, take him
看能不能刺激他的记忆恢复
Down to the crime scene, see if that sparks his memory?
联系芬克的助理达里斯
And get a hold of Fink's assistant Darius.
约他在那里见面
Tell him to meet you down there
让他带上巴希尔·哈伦的资料
With every file he has on Bahir Harun.
你确定我当时在这里
And you're sure I was here?
不着急  不要有压力
Take your time. No pressure.
我是不是应该头疼
Isn't this supposed to be where I get a headache
记忆片段开始闪现
And flashes of memory start overwhelming me
直到所有的片段汇集一起
Until all the pieces come together?
你电影看太多了
Okay, you've seen too many movies.
我可不记得这个
Yeah, that I can't remember.
就像是先有鸡  还是先有蛋
Wow. That's very... Chicken/egg.
欢迎来到我的世界
Welcome to my world.
真诡异
Weird...
真有人能就这样失忆了
That someone can just lose his mind like that.
你确定不认识他
Are you sure you don't recognize him?
我不认识他
I don't think so.
我在这里只做了几个月
But I've only been here a few months.
不过怎样  这是哈伦先生的一切资料
Anyway, here's everything I could find on Mr. Harun.
3年内的买画资料
All purchases, going back three years.
我还是不相信芬克在干造假的勾当
I still can't believe Fink was trafficking in forgeries.
哈伦从芬克那里买画
Harun's purchases from Fink.
数量很多
That's dozens of paintings.
没错  据芬克的前助理罗柯
Yeah, and according to Fink's old assistant Rocco,
所有的画都可能是赝品
Any and all of these could've been forgeries.
朱尔斯·马特森的作品  至少要10万美金
This is a Jules Matterson. This is worth $100,000 easy.
但他只给罗柯1000美金  就把他打发了
Yeah, but you only pay Rocco a grand to knock it off.
芬克可能为了钱干掉哈伦
Fink could've ripped Harun off for millions.
谁说犯罪不需要付出代价
Who says crime doesn't pay?
要是谁榨了我那么多钱
Someone took me for that much,
我也会在背后给他一枪
I could see putting a bullet in his back.
这就解释了为什么哈伦威胁芬克
Well, that explains why Harun went after Fink,
-但是杰呢  -我们得跟哈伦谈谈
-But what about Jay?  -We need to talk to Harun.
贝克特  我讨厌外交豁免权  也讨厌没结果
Beckett, I hate diplomatic immunity as much as the next cop,
至于你  先把那家伙放一边
But as far as you're concerned, forget the guy.
我提交了会面请求
I put in the interview request.
现在归国务院管了  结束
Now it's in the state department's hands, period.
但是长官  其他受害人怎么办
Fine, but, sir, what about the other victim?
患失忆的那家伙
The guy with amnesia. So?
他今晚没地方去
He has nowhere to go tonight.
把他移交给社会福利处
Well, turn him over to social services.
是国务院的事  不是我们的
It's the state's problem, not ours.
我知道  他最终可能在庇护所生活
I know, sir, but he'll probably end up in a homeless shelter.
他是涉案人员  也是潜在的人证
He's a person of interest and a potential witness.
我不想因为体制问题失去他
I would hate to lose him to the system.
那好吧
Okay.
他可以睡我的沙发
But my couch is off-limits.
谢谢长官
Thank you, sir.
这里不是露天广场
It's not the plaza.
但我常溜到这里小憩
But I have snuck many a power nap on this couch over years
你会睡得很安稳的
You should sleep just fine.
很感激  不用和陌生人挤在一起
I'm grateful not to have to go anywhere with strangers.
这不是难事
It's not a problem.
想到有人想杀我  真可怕
It's terrifying to think that someone actually tried to kill me
我不知道凶手是谁  为什么要杀我
And I don't know who it was or why.
他们还逍遥法外
And they're still out there.
所以我们要把那混蛋绳之于法
That's why we're gonna catch the bastard.
但在此之前  我们要查明你的身份
But to do that, we need to find out who you are.
因此明早我们要向媒体发布你的相片
So we're gonna release your photograph to the media tomorrow morning.
如果没人认识我呢
And what if nobody recognizes it?
肯定有人认识你
I'm sure someone will.
如果没人认识  而我又不记得自己
But what if no one does and I don't remember?
那我是谁
Then who am I?
我向你保证  我们不会放弃你
I promise you, we won't give up on you.
自然课老师说  巧克力所含的化学物质
My science teacher says that chocolate contains chemicals
已证实可以减压
That are proven to relieve depression.
太好了  但我更喜欢葡萄酒  陈年佳酿
Ah, it's good. But I prefer grape--aged, bottled and corked.
你们在开冰激凌品尝会
You're having an ice cream tasting,
没人打电话  发短信  留言
And no one called, texted or tweeted.
奶奶和查特分手了
Gram broke it off with Chet.
我建议糖治疗法
So I suggested sugar therapy.
中心公园的日出怎样
What happened to sunrise in central park?
我在开谁玩笑  那是童话
Oh, who am I kidding? It's a fairy tale.
哪个女人不喜欢童话呢
And what woman doesn't want a fairy tale?
-他跟我想的不一样  -如何不同
-He's not who I thought he was.   - How so?
很多不同
Million different little things--you know,
他不开车  很瘦
He doesn't drive, he's skinny,
他会这样笑
Oh, and he has this laugh like...wah-um.
我甚至不会  就像鹅叫那样
I can't even do it. It's like a honking goose kind of...
就是这些情景剧原因而分手
These are sitcom reasons for breaking up.
今早你们还相爱
This morning you were in love.
这怎么可能
What possibly could've happened?
爸爸  后退  火花熄灭了
Dad, back off. The spark died.
她显然重新考虑了
She's obviously reconsidered.
没错
That's right,
我们现在试试这5种伤感口味
And now we're going through the five flavors of grieving.
这是接受冰激凌的第一阶段吗
Oh. Is the first stage accepting the ice cream?
-完全正确  -那算我一份
- Exactly. - Then I'm in.
-早  -他昨晚睡得怎样
-Hey, morning. - Hey. How was he last night?
睡得很沉
He slept like a rock.
霍洛威医生今早来了
Doc Holloway stopped by this morning
给他做认知能力测试
To give him a cognitive abilities test.
算术得分很高
Scored through the roof on the quantitative part.
他数学不错  也许他是会计或金融领域
He's good at math. Maybe he was an engineer
工程师
In accounting or financing.
或只是数学好而已
Or just good at math.
卡塞尔在测试他的绘画能力
Castle is testing his drawing abilities,
看他是不是艺术家
See if he's an artist.
也许他想说服芬克展出他的作品
Maybe he was trying convince Fink to show his work.
我觉得我们应该感激
I suppose we should be thankful
他没说画裸体画
He didn't offer to pose nude.
没错  很庆幸
Yeah, thanks for that.
如果我们要和大使馆人员哈伦谈话
Hey, any idea if we're gonna get
有什么想法吗
To talk to that attacher Harun.
没有回应
Radio silence.
-我们必须查明杰的身份  -没错
- We gotta I.D. Jay.  - Yeap.
-说曹操  曹操到  -已经播了一上午
- Speak of the devil. - Yeah, they been showing it all morning.
-有电话吗  -没有
- Any calls yet?  - No.
查明他的身份前  什么线索也没有
Well, until we figure out who he is, we've got nothing.
结论是什么
So what's the verdict?
你确实抓住了特征
You really captured his soul.
好吧  你不是艺术家
Okay, so you're not an artist.
我肯定你还有其他天赋
I'm sure you have many other talents.
不是记忆天赋而已
Just not a talent for remembering them.
是他  天啊  是他
Oh, that's him! Oh, my god! That's him!
-感谢上帝  -我能为你效劳吗
- Oh, thank god.  - Can I help you?
我想就快查明你的身份了
I think we're about to find out who you are?
-你认识她吗  -是的  是他
- Do you recognize her? - Yes, it's him.
不认识  我连镜子里的自己也不认识
No, but then again, I don't recognize myself on the mirror.
请进去  女士  谢谢  乔伊
Go ahead, ma'am. Thanks. Oh, Joel!
天啊
Oh, my god. Mm.
托丽·威彻斯特  妻子
Tory Westchester, wife.
我很害怕失去你  亲爱的
Oh, I was so scared I lost you. Oh, sweetie.
是真的吗  你不记得一切了
So it's true, you really don't remember anything?
他失忆了
He's suffering from amnesia.
我就知道出事了  我就知道
I knew something was wrong. I knew it.
-杰  你流泪了  -我想是的
- Jay, are you crying? - uh, I think I am.
-有感觉吗  -是的
- Do you feel a connection?   - Yeah.
我快承受不了
It's actually pretty overwhelming.
当然  宝贝  我太爱你了
Of course it is, baby. I love you so much.
我们会挺过去的  不管代价是什么
We will get through this, whatever it takes.
威彻斯特夫人  你们结婚多久了
Ms. Westchester, how long have the two of you been married?
到十月为止两年
Two years this past October.
你说他叫乔伊
And you said his name was Joel...
威彻斯特
Westchester.
亲爱的  看看你
Oh, honey, look at you.
你真的记得我
You do remember me.
爱情可以战胜一切  会好起来的
Oh, love conquers all! Oh, it's all going to be fine!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
怎么了  亲爱的
Oh, what is it? What is it, my darling?
我想他哮喘发作了
I think he's having an asthma attack.
你口袋里有哮喘气雾剂  快拿出来
You have an inhaler in your pocket. Get it.
威彻斯特夫人  你养猫吗
Ms. Westchester, do you have cats?
8只  像乔恩和凯特[真人秀]
Eight, like Jon and Kate.
我想乔伊对猫过敏
I think Joel here is allergic to cats.
真的吗
Really?
威彻斯特夫人  你不是他妻子  对吗
Ms. Westchester, you're not really married to him, are you?
我就是
I could be.
我就是他妻子  为什么我不是
I so could be. Why the hell shouldn't I be?!
十几年来她一直
She's been in and out of mental facilities
进进出出精神病院
For more than ten years.
有记录的每种病态人格她都有
Every personality disorder in the book.
真是不幸
Sorry about that.
又一个"谁想嫁给失忆者"游戏的参赛者
Just another contestant on "who wants to marry an amnesiac?"
贝克特  大使馆人员哈伦先生来了
Beckett, your attacher, Mr.Harun, he's on his way down.
他愿意接受询问
He agreed to talk.
他自己送上门来了
He just showed up voluntarily?
他想平息事态
He wants to stay in control.
这可能是我们唯一的机会
This could be our only shot.
所以一定要让哈伦
Let's make sure that Harun
-好好看看杰  -像无心的一样
- Gets a good look at our friend Jay. - Inadvertent, of course.
如果哈伦认为他杀了杰  他的反应
If Harun thinks that he killed Jay, then his reaction
会告诉我们一切  开工
Could tell us everything we need to know. Let's go.
哈伦先生  你曾是芬克先生的客户是吗
Mr.Harun, you were a client of Mr. Fink's?
没错
That's correct.
-你从他那里买了大量作品  -是的
- You bought a significant number of works from him.  - Yes.
我们认为其中很多作品是伪造的
Well, we believe that many of those works were forgeries.
的确是的
That's correct.
这么说你早就知道那些是赝品
So you're saying that you knew they were fakes?
-当然知道  -那你还买
- Of course I knew. - And you bought them anyway?
怎么说呢  我家里有很多朋友
I have many friends back home whose wives are,
他们的妻子总不满足
How shall we say, uh, demanding.
那她们要赝品干什么
And what do demanding wives have to do with any of this?
大家都知道  女性比较肤浅
Well, we all know that the fairer sex can be shallow.
当然不包括你  探长
Not you, of course, detective--
你是个聪明又开放的美国女性
A smart, liberated American woman.
但是我朋友的妻子
But my friends' wives,
她们想要品牌包  如古奇
They want a bag that says, um, "Gucci."
她们不在乎是谁生产的
They don't care who made the bag
只要包上有那个标签
As long as it has that signature.
关于画作  同理可知
And it's the same with paintings.
比起作品本身
They are more appreciative of--of the signature
她们更看重签名
Than of the-- the work itself.
我的朋友们不愿意老花大把钞票
And my friends don't always want to spend top dollar
去买那些真货  就托维克多弄个赝品
On authentic pieces, so Victor would commission a copy.
朋友可以省钱  而我赚钱
My friends save money, I get rich...
女人也会以为
And the wives get to think that they have...
-往左挪一步  -好
- Move to your left, just a drop.- Yeah.
所以你只从芬克那里买赝品
So you only bought fakes from Fink?
不全是  他也提供一些真货
No. He would also source originals
给那些有品位的男人们
For those husbands with taste.
我很乐意提供  尽管真货赚的少
I was happy to provide, even though originals pay less...
觉得眼熟吗
He look familiar?
没有  抱歉
No, sorry.
芬克先生被杀的当晚
The night that Mr. Fink was murdered,
案发不久前你曾跟他通过话
You called him not long before he was killed.
是的  警探
That's correct, detective.
他要我过去一趟  说有幅画给我看
He--he told me to come by, that he had a painting for me.
我大约9点45到那  但他打发我走
I showed up around 9:45,  but he sent me away.
打发你走
Sent you away?
是的  他当时在跟另一个人争吵
Yes, he was arguing with a man.
-吵什么  -不知道
- About what? - I have no idea.
如他所愿  我离开了
I respected his wishes
然后去诺布餐厅吃饭
And went for dinner at Nobu.
你能描述一下这个人吗
Do you think you could describe this man?
拜托  有必要继续这种无聊游戏吗
Please. Must we continue with this ridiculous charade?
我们都知道他就站在那里
When we both know he is standing right there?
那么  如果没有其他事情
Now if that is all...
哈伦先生  我还没问完
Mr.Harun,  I'm not quite done yet.
但我说完了
Ah, but I am.
希望你们过得愉快
Have a nice day.
谢谢
Thanks.
对一个有外交豁免权的人来说
For a guy with diplomatic immunity,
他也不算特别有外交手腕
He wasn't very diplomatic.
哈伦在利用豁免权做挡箭牌
Harun's hiding behind his immunity.
他知道的远不止这些
He knows more than he's saying.
也许  但他的不在场证明是真的
Maybe. But his alibi is good.
诺布餐厅的监控录像录到
Nobu has him on security video
他晚上9点55进门
Entering at 9:55 p.m.,
也就是报警前19分钟
19 minutes before the 9-1-1 call about shots fired.
他不是凶手
He's not our guy.
但是  不是他开的枪
Well, just because he didn't pull the trigger
并不意味着他与此案无关
Doesn't mean he wasn't involved.
杰中枪了
And just because Jay was shot
也不意味着他是清白的
Doesn't mean he wasn't into something shady.
这可能就是他中枪的原因
It could be the reason he was shot.
哈伦说他看到杰跟芬克在争吵
Harun said he saw Jay arguing with Fink.
我们要搞清楚为什么杰会在画廊
We need to figure out why Jay was at the gallery.
如果不知道他到底是谁  就不能搞清楚
And we can't do that if we don't know who the hell he is.
我们已经查过一遍了  只是一堆垃圾
We've been through this. It's just a bunch of junk.
但如果我们仔细清理一下
But if we take a look at everything
手头的所有资料  也许会有所发现
We know about him collectively, maybe a picture will emerge.
这些钥匙没什么特别
Nothing distinctive about these keys.
确实  那个塑料袋也的确缩小了范围
Yeah, and that plastic bag really narrows it down.
他患有哮喘病
Okay, he's got asthma,
对猫过敏  爱读书
He's allergic to cats, he reads--
还精通数学  不会画画
And he's good at math and he can't draw.
综合看来  他只是个数学健将
Put it together, he's your average math athlete
口袋里还装着很多垃圾
With a lot of crap in his pocket.
-探长  -谢谢
- Detective. - Thank you.
蕾妮对他外套的检验报告
It's from Lanie. It's the forensics report on his coat.
也许他的驾照还缝在里衬
Maybe his driver's license was sewn into the lining.
有火药残留物
Gunpowder residue.
这么说他是被近距离射击的
So he was shot at close range
还有咖啡渍  糖粒  和牛奶印迹
Mm-hmm. Coffee stains, sugar granules, traces of milk.
可以知道他是怎么喝咖啡的了
Well, we know how he takes his coffee.
-动物的毛  -不是猫毛
- Animal hairs. - Not cat hairs.
-我怎么忽略了这个  -忽略什么
- How could I have missed this? - Missed what?
-知道这是什么吗  -知道  食品袋
- Do you know what this is?  - Yeah, it's a grocery bag.
不  不仅仅是食品袋
No, it's not just a grocery bag.
这个袋子能告诉我们杰的真实身份
It's the bag that's gonna tell us exactly who Jay is.
为什么硬拉我回画廊
Why are you dragging me back to the art gallery?
不是去画廊  是那条街
Not to the art gallery, to the street.
-不见了 -什么不见了
- Ah, it's gone. - What's gone?
那只狗  这就是他带着食品袋的原因
The dog. That's why he had the bag,
为了用袋子清理狗粪
To clean up after his dog.
你怎么知道那就是他的狗
How do you know it was his dog?
那他为什么拿个袋子
Well, why else would he have a bag?
为什么过了午夜还有一只狗
Why else would there be a dog tied up
被拴在一栋商业大楼外
Outside a commercial building after midnight?
可能有人把狗偷走了
Maybe someone stole it.
帮我接动物管理处
Get me animal control.
挂狗牌的都是24小时内收养的
All the canines with I.D. tags we picked up in the last 24.
大部分是主人不小心弄丢了
Mostly their owners lost 'em accidentally
我们打去电话  他们就松了口气
And are relieved when we call.
卡塞尔
Castle.
多漂亮的家伙啊
Oh. Who's a good girl?
这只是从148大街西26号捡回的
That one's from 148 west 26th.
就是芬克的画廊那里
That's Fink's gallery.
露西
Lucy.
你叫杰里米·普瑞斯威科
Your name is Jeremy Preswick.
已经和机动车管理部的照片核对过了
We checked it against your D.M.V. photo,
是你的真实身份
And it's a positive I.D.
-杰里米·普瑞斯威科  -你今年34岁
- Jeremy Preswick. - You are 34 years old,
住在特里贝克地区华伦街82号
And you live at 82 warren street in Tribeca.
你没有什么亲人
You don't really have any family.
父母几年前过世
Your parents passed away a few years ago,
也没有兄弟姐妹
And you don't have any siblings.
但我们联系到了你的前妻爱玛·卡恩斯
But we did manage to get a hold of your ex-wife, Emma Carnes.
前妻
Ex-wife?
我离过婚
I'm divorced?
没错
Yeah.
抱歉  你前妻听说你的情况后很关心你
Sorry. Your ex sounded pretty concerned.
我们认为这可能是
And we figured that would be the fastest way
弄清事情原委最快捷的方法
Of putting together the details,
也对你和我们的调查都有很大帮助
Which would be great for you and for our investigation.
你们看着办吧
If you think it'll help.
我连我有前妻都不记得
I have an ex-wife that I can't remember.
有人还觉得你很幸运呢
Hey, some men would consider you lucky.
-这边请  -谢谢
- Here you go. - Thanks.
-你好  杰里米  -你好
- Hello, Jeremy. - Hey.
谢谢你能来  我真的很感激
Thank you for coming. I appreciate it.
没关系
Sure.
我们离婚了吧
So we're divorced.
是的
Yeah.
过来帮我  肯定觉得很奇怪吧
Must be weird, coming here to try to help me out, huh?
有点
A little.
请坐
Please take a seat.
他怎么了
So what happened to him?
我们也想知道
That's what we are trying to figure out.
你能告诉我们有关杰里米的事情吗
Is there anything you can tell us about Jeremy?
说什么呢
Well, like what?
比如  他在哪里工作
Like, uh, where he works.
据我所知  他已经没有工作了
Well, as far as I know, he doesn't anymore.
你坐在这里  让我感觉很怪
Okay, this is weird with you sitting right there.
我也想听
Tell me about it.
你在沃顿商学院拿了经济学博士学位
You have a PHD in economics from Wharton.
你曾在经济和战略电视台旗下
Uh, you had a consulting business
经营一家咨询公司
In channel Economics and Strategy.
你很聪明
You're smart.
简直聪明绝顶
Like, crazy smart.
他曾经营过一家公司
Had a business?
是的  去年他把公司卖了
Yeah, yeah, he sold it last year.
你知道为什么吗
Do you know why?
不知道  我也觉得不可思议
No. I thought it was weird.
他热爱他的事业
He loved the business.
我们为什么离婚
Why'd we split up?
关于这个我向朋友们抱怨了很久
I've ranted for hours to girlfriends about that.
我猜我肯定被你骂得一文不值
I'm guessing I don't come off so well in that rant.
那时你就是个混蛋
You were a jerk.
但我也有错
But so was I.
也许因为我们结婚太早了
I mean, the truth is, We probably got married too young.
我认不出你  对此我很抱歉
Look, I'm sorry that I don't recognize you.
但我觉得你很善良  而且很美
But you seem incredibly nice and you're gorgeous,
我确信当时完全是我的错
And I'm certain that it was entirely my fault
以至于毁了我们的婚姻
That marriage fell apart.
看到了吧  这就是
See that. That's...
我那时爱的家伙
The guy I fell in love with--
风趣  贴心  谦虚
Funny, sweet, self-deprecating.
你知道杰里米
Do you know what Jeremy
最近在做什么吗
Had been doing with himself recently?
据我所知
As far as I know,
只在找年轻性感的女人交往
He was dating the youngest, hottest women he could find
都不嫌放下马桶座圈麻烦
And not bothering to put the toilet seat down.
你知不知道他在切尔西的
And do you have any idea what he might have been doing
维克多·芬克画廊干什么
At the Victor Fink gallery in Chelsea?
不知道  抱歉  我们几乎一年没说话
No, I'm sorry. But we haven't even spoken in almost a year.
好吧  我们现在去杰里的家
Um, well, we're on our way to Jeremy's apartment
看能不能让他想起什么
To see if it sparks anything.
你愿意一起来吗
Would you mind coming along?
你也许能把一些线索联系起来
You might be able to put things in some context.
觉得眼熟吗
Look familiar?
不
Nope.
你们可以说  我是最差的目击者
You can say it. I'm the worst witness ever.
你做得还不错
Ah, you're doing fine.
一个钱包
A wallet.
看来你没有被抢劫
Well, I don't think you were mugged.
介意我到处转转  看看抽屉之类的吗
Do you mind if I poke around, open some drawers?
把我家当自己家吧[西班牙语]
Mi casa que no recuerdo es tu casa.
瞧  西班牙语还不错
Hey, look at that. Rockin' the spanish.
我们大三在马德里读书
We did junior year in Madrid.
听来不错
That sounds nice.
这些是俄语文学著作集
Here's the rest of your Russian literature collection.
读书很有追求  普瑞斯威科先生
You are a very ambitious reader, Mr. Preswick.
你总是希望有更多的时间来读书
You always wanted more time to read.
估计现在我得全部重读了
I guess I'm gonna have to start over now.
也不算是坏事
Ah, it's not such a bad thing.
我第一次读《一桶白葡萄酒》
What I wouldn't give to read "the cask of amontillado"
真是无比痴狂  或任何斯蒂芬·金的书
For the first time...or any Stephen King.
好消息是  你可以再次
Ah, silver lining--you get to read all my books
欣赏所有我的作品了
For the first time again.
有线索吗
Anything?
这里很零乱
It's pretty sparse.
是一个独自生活很久的男人
Like a guy who spent a lot of time alone.
就是  我以为你至少有个垫子
Yeah, I thought you'd have more of a slick pad
其他也收拾整齐
Done up with more stuff.
泰格利亚  这幅画可不便宜啊
Hey. Taglia. This is a pretty pricey painting.
艾玛  你知道杰里米是在市里的
Emma, do you know if Jeremy bought that painting
画廊买的这幅画吗
At a gallery in the city?
不是  那是我们
No, we... Bought that together
在锡耶纳度蜜月的时候一起买的
On our honeymoon in Siena.
-真不敢相信你还留着  -为什么
- I can't believe you still have it. - Why?
离婚协议的其中一项
Well, part of the divorce settlement
就是把这幅画卖掉  然后分掉这笔钱
Was to sell it and split the cash.
当时估价二十多万  你给了我一半
It appraised for over 200 grand. You sent me my half.
真有趣
That's funny.
有关这幅画的事如此熟悉
There's something about it that's so familiar.
或者我仅仅只是喜欢这幅画
Or maybe I just like it.
卡塞尔
Castle.
九毫米口径的
It's a 9 millimeter...
少了五发子弹
With five bullets missing.
弹道测试证明
So ballistics confirmed
在杰里米家发现的抢
That the gun found in Jeremy's apartment
就是杀死芬克的那把
Was the same one that was used to kill Fink,
我们只需知道
And we just need to know
杰里是否有可能就是开枪的人
If it's possible that Jeremy was the shooter.
鉴证组的确在他外套上
C.S.U. did find gun residue
发现了火药残留物
On his coat.
那只能说明他是被近距离射击的
Well, that just means that he was shot at close range.
假设是杰里米拿着抢
Like if Jeremy were holding the gun,
与芬克扭打在一起  芬克把枪转向他
Struggled with Fink, Fink managed to turn the gun around
然后开火
And it went off?
芬克手腕上的淤青
Well, these abrasions on Fink's wrists
正好与你刚才说的吻合
Are certainly consistent with that.
那他为何会把枪留在公寓里
Well, then why would he have left the gun in his apartment?
霍洛威医生说过  他可能处于神游状态
Doc Holloway said he was probably in a fugue state,
比如梦游  他可能丢下枪然后
Like sleepwalking. He could've dropped the gun off
然后又重新回到画廊
And then went back out again.
好吧  我糊涂了
Okay, am I  missing something?
我以为你们抓到了凶手
I thought you were supposed to be happy
应该高兴才是
After you caught the killer.
我为什么杀人
Why'd I do it?
我们不知道原因
We don't know why.
你需要聘请一位律师
You'll be appointed a lawyer.
我知道艾玛想给你找一个
I know that Emma wants to help hire someone,
我想钱不是问题
And I don't think money will be an issue.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
不知道你为什么谢我  普瑞斯威科先生
I don't know why you're thanking me, Mr. Prestwick.
我们以谋杀罪逮捕了你
We just arrested you for murder.
没错  但那不是你们的错
Yeah, well, it's not your fault.
对一个自认为是受害者
You guys have been nothing but incredibly nice
又一无所知的白痴  你们已经够好了
To a babbling idiot  who thought he was a victim
感觉就像我欺骗了你们
It's like I tricked you.
祝你好运  杰里米
Good luck, Jeremy.
你们查明真相之后  能告诉我吗
If you figure it out, would you let me know?
当然
Of course.
知道原因的话  可能会好过一点
I just think it would be easier knowing why.
为根本不记得的杀人而内疚
The guy is guilty of a murder he can't remember.
真让人郁闷
That just sucks.
我是说  如果你打算杀人
I mean, if you're gonna kill someone, get caught,
被抓后得在监狱里度过余生
Spend the rest of your life in prison, at least
至少你还知道自己为何坐牢
You have the satisfaction of knowing why you did it--
仇恨  报复  破坏  甚至公路抢劫
Hatred, revenge, hell, maybe even cut you off on the highway.
即使找到杀人动机  杰里米还是不知道
But Jeremy won't even have that even if we do find motive
因为他不记得杀人的意义何在
Because he won't remember why it meant anything to him.
我跟你一样  卡塞尔  觉得郁闷
I'm with you, Castle. It sucks.
下一步怎么办
So what next?
我们把书面报告呈交给地方检察官
We, uh, submit the paperwork to the D.A.
可地方检察官也需要动机啊  不是吗
But the D.A. will need motive, right?
不  证据说话  确凿的证据
No. Evidence speaks. Smoking gun.
你不想知道他为什么杀人吗
But don't you want to know why he did it?
想  但事实上  我们并不需要知道
Yeah, but the truth is, is that we don't need it.
地方检察官不需要
The D.A. doesn't need it.
但你和我呢
But you and me?
我昨晚彻夜难眠  你呢
I know I couldn't sleep last night. Could you?
这里肯定有答案
There's gotta be an answer here,
他生活里的东西肯定能解释一切
Something in his life that makes it all make sense.
举起手来  不许动
Hands! Show 'em.
吓死我了
Oh, that gets the heart rate going.
卡恩斯女士  你在这里做什么
Ms. Carnes, what are you doing here?
拿一些露西的东西
Getting Lucy's things.
处方药
Prescription.
我想得由我保管了
I guess I have custody now.
很抱歉吓到你了  我们不知道你在这里
I'm sorry to surprise you.  We didn't know you'd be here.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事  我只是突然想到
Yeah. I guess I just thought for half a second
这于我和他是一次难得又怪异机会
That this would be a bizarre second chance for Jer and me.
-很蠢  是吗  -不  一点都不蠢
- Stupid, right? - No, it's not stupid.
发现他是个杀人凶手之后
And to find out that he's a murderer...
当我再次见到他时  我
When I saw him again, I...
那么多年的争吵
All those years of petty arguments
导致后来的分离  都不算什么了
Thatore us apart didn't seem to matter.
就像  我们初次见面
It was--it was like we first met.
我找回了那种感觉
You know, I felt that thing.
然后我们来这里  看见他不愿意卖掉它
And then we came here and I saw that he didn't sell it,
我觉得他也对我念念不忘
And I thought maybe he still had feelings for me, too.
你是指这幅
Do you mean the painting
你们俩蜜月时买的油画
That the two of you bought on your honeymoon?
是的  不是因为我们想买
Yeah, we didn't buy it because we wanted to.
而是必须买
We had to.
当时我们在锡耶纳的一家画廊
We were in the artist's studio in Siena
杰里米从画架上拿起它
And Jeremy picked it up off the easel.
画还没干透呢  他总是冒冒失失的
He was always goofing around. The artist went crazy.
那个画家都快疯了
It was still drying.
为这个爱情印记我们笑了好久
We laughed for a week about our little love smudge.
当我看见他没有卖掉它  我就在想
And then when I saw that he didn't sell it, I thought,
或许
Maybe...
但我是在自欺欺人
But I was kidding myself.
为什么这么说
What do you mean?
没有手指印  就是这里
No thumbprint. It should be right here.
他卖掉了原来那幅画  这个是副本
He sold ours. This one's just a copy.
卡恩斯女士  你确定吗
Ms. Carnes, are you sure?
当然  确信无疑
Of course I'm sure.
是赝品
It's a fake.
我们知道谁倒卖赝品
And we know who dealt in fakes.
这就能将杰里米和芬克联系起来了
That's gotta be Jeremy's connection to Fink.
也解释了为何杰里米会在画廊
That's gotta be why Jeremy was at the gallery.
如果像哈伦说的杰里米和芬克在争吵
And if Jeremy and Fink were arguing like Harun said,
或许就是为了真品
Maybe it was over the original.
如果这是赝品  那真品在哪里
And if that's a fake, then where is the original?
当然  小心那幅画
Absolutely, and, uh-- Careful with that one.
好的  谢谢  再见[法语]
Oui. Oui, merci. A bientot.
哈伦先生  这么快就走了吗
Leaving us so soon, Mr. Harun?
怎么了  我还要赶飞机
Oh, what now?  I have a plane to catch.
这次旅行收获了不错的作品吗
Make any interesting art acquisitions on this trip?
确实有些收获
Actually, yes.
介意我们看一看吗
Mind if we take a look?
很抱歉  我没有时间
I'm sorry.  I just don't have the time.
挤出时间
Make time.
"外交豁免权"的哪一部分
What part of "diplomatic immunity"
你们不太清楚
Are you not clear on?
你每次这样说时
See, every time you say something like that,
就让我觉得你在隐瞒什么
It makes me think that you have something to hide.
你永远也找不出来  真糟糕
It's too bad that you will never find out.
请出示驾照和行驶证
License and registration, please.
-什么  为什么  -你们并排停车
- What? Why? - You are double parked.
这是纽约  人人都并排停车
This is New York. Everyone double parks.
-他是妨碍公务吗  -我想是的
- Is he resisting arrest? - I believe so.
站到这边来
Step over here.
我们要查车
We're gonna have to search your car.
你没有权利这么做
You have no right to do this.
我没看到任何外交牌照
I don't see any diplomatic plates.
豁免权不包括汽车
And immunity doesn't extend to a car service.
哈伦先生  你有两条路可选
Mr. Harun, this can go one of two ways,
要么合作  说出我们想要知道的
You can either cooperate and tell me what I need to know
要么我致电国务院
Or I can call the state department
通知他们你有一件艺术品
And inform them that you have a piece of artwork
和一件谋杀案有很大关联
That's at the center of our murder investigation.
最后我发现  纽约小报
And the last I checked, the New York tabloids
只会略微提及你的外交身份
Could give a rat's ass about your diplomatic status.
他们会用你的照片做头条
They'll just print your photograph with a headline
题目是"外交混蛋"
That says "diplomatic douche bag."
好吧  你们想知道什么
Fine. What would you like to know?
枪击案一名受害人家中
There's a fake version of this painting
发现了这幅油画的赝品
Found in one of our shooting victim's apartments.
-能告知是怎么回事吗  -我怎么知道
- Can you tell us how it got there?  - How would I know this?
因为赝品
Because the fake painting is
在真品曾经所在的地方
Where the real painting used to be
现在真品在你手里
And now you have the real painting.
我只知道  这是我让芬克
All I know is that I asked Fink to acquire it
为我的客户所寻  当他说有了之后
For a client of mine.  When he said he had it,
我以为他找到画主并买了下来
I assumed he'd tracked down the owner and made a deal.
当我那晚到画廊后  他又打发我走了
But when I went to the gallery that evening, he sent me away,
就像我说过的
Just like I told you.
故事很精彩  哈伦先生
That's a great story, Mr. Harun,
可如果芬克打发你时  你是空手而归的
But if Fink sent you away empty-handed,
你又怎么会有这幅画吗
Why do you have the painting?
因为早上我接到一个人的电话
Because I got a call from a man this morning
说他有这幅画  想要出售
That said he had it for a price.
是谁
Who was it?
芬克的新助手达里斯
It was Fink's new assistant Darius.
这太荒谬了
This is crazy.
我已经说过了
I told you already,
芬克先生被杀时我在上课
I was in class when Mr. Fink was killed.
-没人记得见过你  -我坐在后排
- Nobody remembers seeing you there.  - I sat in the back.
淘气的学生才那样
The naughty kids always do.
杰里米为油画找芬克对质那晚
You were at the gallery the night that Jeremy
你在画廊
Confronted Fink about the painting.
听着  显然这里面有误会
Listen, there's obviously been some kind of misunderstanding.
这也是误会吗
Was this a misunderstanding as well?
这是普瑞斯威科公寓管理员签署的声明
It's a signed statement from the super at Prestwick's building
承认他拿了你1000美元
Admitting that he took a $1,000 bribe from you
允许你进入杰里的公寓
To allow you into Jeremy's apartment
于是你换走了那幅画
So that you could switch out the paintings.
抱歉  有必要从头开始说明一下
I'm sorry. Shoulda come clean from the start.
芬克想要那幅画
Fink wanted the painting.
他告诉我  跟普瑞斯威科买那幅画
He told me to buy it from Prestwick,
但这家伙不卖
But the guy wouldn't sell.
所以芬克让我画了幅赝品
So Fink had me paint a fake.
是的  我贿赂了管理员...
And, yeah, I-I bribed the super to...
为了和真品调包
Switch it with the real thing.
这很愚蠢
It was stupid,
但芬克威胁说  如果我不干就要被解雇
But...Fink threatened to fire me if I didn't.
全部都是你干的  达里斯
It was all you, Darius.
你将油画调包  然后吞掉了
You switched out the paintings, you pocketed
芬克给你买画的钱
The money that Fink gave you to buy it.
是芬克  他指使的我
It was Fink. He manipulated me.
不  你说谎
No, that is just a lie.
你还说了一个谎  你的名字
And you know what else is a lie? Your name.
达里斯·兰利是你的室友
Darius Langley is your roommate.
很聪明  用他的身份在画廊找工作
Pretty smart, using his identity to land a job at the gallery.
不过我猜你有两次造假罪
Though I guess it'd be pretty tough to get hired
很难再找到工作
With two felony counts of counterfeiting, though,
是吗  乔治
Isn't it, George?
你的档案挺厚的  海勒先生
You've got quite a rap sheet, Mr. Heller.
如果再次入罪  你就要被关很久啦
Hmm. One more strike, you go away for a long time.
所以当普瑞斯威科知道真相时
Which is why you couldn't afford Prestwick calling the cops
你知道不能让他报警  于是向他开枪
When he found out the truth, and so you shot him.
当他倒下时  你又朝芬克开枪
And then when he went down, you shot Fink as well.
你以为你可以告我谋杀吗
You think you're gonna pin this murder on me?
不可能
No way.
你没证据
You don't got jack.
仔细看
Read carefully.
你贿赂了管理员  两次
You bribed the super...  Twice.
第二次是莱恩和埃斯波西托警探
And the second time was four hours after
带普瑞斯威科到画廊的四小时后
Detectives Ryan and Esposito brought Prestwick to the gallery
你意识到他已经失忆
And you realized that he had lost his memory.
你把枪放在那里的
You planted the gun.
挥棒落空
Swing and a miss.
三振出局
Strike three. You're out.
这真美
Ah, it's a beaut.
-不是吗  -我特别喜欢手指印
- Isn't it? - I especially love the fingerprint.
我也是  虽然我不记得了
Me, too.  Even if I can't remember,
但仍能感觉到  这是我生活的一部分
It still somehow feels a part of me.
杰里
Hey, Jer.
准备好走了吗
Ready to rock?
谢谢你能来
Thanks for coming.
还记得露西吗
You remember Lucy?
-不  -她肯定记得你了
- No. - She certainly remembers you.
谢谢  伙计们
Well, hey, thanks, guys.
因为你们  因谋杀被也没那么糟
You made getting arrested for murder really not so bad.
谢谢
Thank you.
-那你们两个是否打算  -卡塞尔
- So are you two gonna...- Castle.
没关系  结果...
It's okay. The answer is...
谁知道呢  我们彼此喜欢
Who knows? I like him and he likes me.
-现在  这样就够了  -再见
- And right now, that's enough.  - Well, see you.
我猜如果我又失忆  知道该去哪里了
I guess if I ever lose my memory again, I'll know where to come.
是啊  再见
Right.  See ya.
一个人背着15年的记忆
One of 'em has 15 years of baggage--
结婚  离婚  另一个却是第一次约会
Marriage, divorce-- the other's on a first date.
-你觉得他们能坚持多久  -很可能会很久
- How long you think that'll last? - Hopefully for a long time.
贝克特探长  我不知道你是个浪漫之人
Why, detective Beckett. I had no idea you were a romantic.
我睡觉时带着枪  你肯定也不知道这点
I also sleep with a gun. Bet you didn't know that either.
你呢  卡塞尔  你觉得会坚持多久
What about you, Castle? How long you think it'll last?
这只是我作为作家的看法
Well, I guess it's just the writer in me,
我期望大团圆结局
But I'm hoping for a happy ending.
看看现在是谁仪表不整
Look who's doing the walk of shame now.
-我和贝克特一起  -是吗
- I was with Beckett. - Really?
刚结了个案子
Uh, wrapping up a case.
趁你们都还年轻  你该吻她
Aha. Well, you should kiss that girl while you're both young.
你怎么了  拿的是什么
What's going on with you? What have you got there?
查特给的  很浪漫吧
Oh, it's from Chet. Isn't it romantic?
查特送凋谢的花给你
Chet sent you a dead flower?
这是有史以来别人
It is the most romantic thing
为我做过的最浪漫的事
That anyone has ever done for me.
我彻夜办案  或许反应有点慢
I've been up all night, so I might be a little slow.
这是毕业舞会送他的钮扣花
Well, it's the boutonniere I gave him prom night.
他保存着  收藏在毕业册里
He saved it, tucked it into a yearbook,
昨晚他送来  附着一张字条
And he sent it over last night with a note...
写着  我能给
Saying...  Would I give...
给他第二次机会吗
Give him a second chance.
最近总发生这种事啊
Well, there's a lot of that going around these days.
我有点害怕
And I'm scared.
我是说  假如行不通呢
I mean, what if it doesn't work out?
行得通又怎么办呢
What if it does?
这就是生活的代价
That's the cost of living.
我只是不想破坏它
I just don't want to ruin this.
这个  已经凋谢了
This... Is dead.
你还活着
You are not.
是时候开始新生活了
Time to start making some new memories.
孩子  你怎么这么聪明
Boy, how did you get so smart?
虎父无犬子
Must be my dad.
是吗  你爸爸
You. Your dad.